A Guide to the United States War Department, Revolutionary War Payrolls 1776-1784
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Unites States War Department, Revolutionary War Payrolls, 1776-1784
The Library of Virginia
36989
3.75 cubic feet
United States. War Dept.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information unavailable
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (Cabinet 81; Rolls 92-114 pertain to Virginia - Guide available in microfilm area).
Scope and Content
Consists of bound photostats of monthly payrolls from Virginia regiments during the Revolutionary War. The bulk of the payrolls date between 1777 and 1779. They contain the name, rank, pay per month, additional pay, subsistence, whole amount in dollars, and casualties or remarks (includes furlough and sick). A total amount of pay is listed for the officer or soldier and a total for the company for that month. There is usually an additional payroll listing only field and staff officers for that regiment. The payrolls are listed in order by regiment number. The last two boxes contain consolidated regiments and miscellaneous organizations including Illinois Regiments, artillery, dragoons, etc. Both Virginia Continental and State Line units are represented in these payrolls, but mostly Continental Line units are present.
These bound photostats were used by H.J. Eckenrode for Virginia Soldiers of the American Revolution (see bibliography below), but the microfilm contains all of the documentation used to create the Revolutionary War compiled military service records and may contain more information.
Arrangement
Arranged numerically by regiment with Consolidated Virginia Regiments & Miscellaneous Virginia Regiments to the rear of the collection.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Virginia soldiers of the American Revolution. Compiled by H.J. Eckenrode. Richmond: Virginia State Library and Archives, 1989.
Contents List
- 1st Virginia Regiment, 1777-1779 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1st Virginia State Regiment, 1777-1780 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 2nd Virginia Regiment, 1777-1780 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 2nd Virginia State Regiment, 1776-1778 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 3rd Virginia Regiment, 1776-1780 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 4th Virginia Regiment, 1777-1778 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 5th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1779 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 6th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1779 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 7th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1783 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 8th Virginia Regiment, 1778-1779 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 9th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1779 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 10th Virginia Regiment, 1778-1779 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 11th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1778 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 12th Virginia Regiment, 1777-1778 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- 13th Virginia Regiment, 1776-1778 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- 14th Virginia Regiment, 1777-1778 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- 15th Virginia Regiment, 1777-1778 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- 1st & 10th Virginia Regiment, 1779 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 3rd & 4th Virginia Regiment, 1779 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- 3rd & 7th Virginia Regiment, 1778 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- 4th, 8th, & 12th Virginia Regiment, 1778-1779 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- 5th & 9th Virginia Regiment, 1778 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- 5th & 11th Virginia Regiment, 1779 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- 11th & 15th Virginia Regiment, 1778 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Virginia Organizations, 1780-1784 (Box 10, Folder 4)